Suraj Anand

Email: surya13493@gmail.com Contact: +91 8860226180 Address- Gurugram, India.

#### **Career Summary**

Results-oriented, Focused and Quick-learner web developer with 2 years of experience in designing Real-time data monitoring system, E-commerce portals, & Informative websites for various domestic and international clients. Willingness to learn new technologies and tools.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap.
- Development: WAMP, LAMP, AWS, Heroku, Bitbucket, Git.
- CMS: WordPress, Magento(Beginner).
- Database Systems: MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Operating System: Windows, Linux.

## **Work Experience**

**Projects:** https://suraj-anand.herokuapp.com

## Web developer & UI Designer, Digital Projects, Jan 2018 - Present

- Designed and built effective and attractive user interfaces for a variety of platforms
- Developed E-commerce & Informative Static websites for Domestic & International clients.
- Participated in meetings in order to transform client needs into proposed product designs.
- Responsible for full life-cycle software development and maintenance.

### Software Developer & UI Designer, Soreva Energy, Dec 2016 – Dec 2017

- Developed a PV Solar Real-Time data monitoring system for National Institute of Solar Energy.
- Designed an application to monitor SRRA(Solar Radiation Resource Assessment) station for analysis of meteorological data in real time from all sites stations to a single centralized platform for NIWE.
- Developed the application with these salient features: Dashboards, Data Visualization, Reports, Export functionality, Real-time solar plant performance monitoring & Environmental contribution.
- Worked with team to develop a proprietary, secure, and centralized database.
- Developed application prototypes and participated in client meetings.
- Responsible for full life-cycle software development and maintenance.

# UI Designer, Avencher, Sep 2016 – Dec 2016

- Designed effective and attractive user interfaces for a variety of platforms.
- Worked on several projects and provided end-to-end solutions to clients.

## **Professional Qualification**

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering, United Group of Institution, Allahabad, 2012-2016.

#### **Training and Certificate Details**

- Core PHP, Udemy, 2018.
- WordPress, Udemy, 2018.
- MTA: Database Fundamentals Certified 2016 Certificate
- MTA: Java Development Certified 2014